Records of the National Society Of New England Women, 1895-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
National Society of New England Women records
1895-2011
National Society of New England Women
MS 372
188 boxes (139.75 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
The NSNEW records document the history of the society, as well as the general goals and activities of patriotic societies in the United States. The records may also be studied for the genealogical origins of its members and ongoing social activities. Materials include correspondence, minutes, genealogical records, membership applications and indexes, photographs, scrapbooks, clippings, memorabilia, and other material dating from its founding.
The National Society of New England Women was incorporated by the state of New York on February 20, 1895. Its founder, Mrs. William Gerry (Emma) Slade, and fourteen other charter members met at Mrs. Slade's home in New York City on January 24, 1895 (Founder's or Organization Day), to establish the organization. The object of the society was "to promote social and intellectual intercourse among its members, to offer advice and assistance to women of New England birth or ancestry residing in portions of the United States other than New England."
In 1913 the society was reorganized under Mrs. Henry Clark Coe as President General. The members in New York City became the New York City Colony and the other branches which had formed across the country during the early years of the society also joined the national organization. The records of the New York City Colony contain the earliest history of the society.
In 1929 the mission of the society was revised to read: "to bring together, in social relations, women of New England ancestry, to engage in patriotic, civic and philanthropic work, thus to perpetuate the lofty ideals and examples of their forefathers." The society's activities continue to reflect the genealogical, patriotic, historical, educational, and charitable goals of its founders.
Membership requirements have varied slightly over the years, but membership has been open to women over eighteen years of age who are descendants of early New Englanders, having ancestors born in New England before the ratification of the Constitution in 1789. The prospective member submits genealogical proof and, once accepted by the colony and national organization, may join as a regular member. Other membership categories are member-at-large (for members in regions where no colonies have been organized), junior members (age six through eighteen), and cradle roll (from birth through age six).
Colonies are established in areas where interest is shown by five or more individuals who meet national membership requirements. Colonies meet regularly and may hear lectures about historical, genealogical, or other topics of interest, promote historical interest in their region, or support charitable work. In addition to local charities, the colonies contribute to charities sponsored by the national society.
In 1946 the society voted to make the New England Kurn Hattin Homes, Inc., of Vermont, residential schools for underprivileged boys and girls, a permanent interest of the society. In 1956 the Clarke School for the Deaf in Northampton, Massachusetts, was added as another permanent interest. The society as a whole has also sponsored student loan funds at various colleges, the Helping Hand Fund to aid needy members, and the Soldier's, Sailor's, and Airmen's Club in New York City, among other projects.
The society holds an annual congress at which it conducts it business. A Board of Managers is formed from officers and committee chairs to direct society activities. The yearbooks contain organizational information about the officers and committees, as well as colony data.
The NSNEW records consist of correspondence, minutes, genealogical records, membership applications and indexes, photographs, scrapbooks, clippings, memorabilia, and other material dating from its founding in 1895. The bulk of the records date from c. 1913 when the organization became a national society. Earlier national documentation may be found in the records of the New York City Colony.
While the records will most often be used to study the history of the society, they also reflect the general goals and activities of patriotic societies in the United States, many of which were founded during the same period in American history. The membership of the society mirrors its beliefs and, in its fluctuating size, the patriotic inclinations of the entire country. This portion of the United States' population may also be studied for its genealogical origins and ongoing social activities.
This collection is organized into ten series:
I. National--General
II. National--Annual Congresses and Conventions
III. National Officers
IV. National Boards
V. National Committees
VI. National Yearbooks
VII. National Membership Applications
VIII. National Proofs
IX. National Card Indexes
X. Colonies
Memorabilia and Oversize Materials
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection with the following restriction:
Collection is stored offsite; researchers must request boxes 48 hours in advance.
Note: this collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to collection are expected and may not be reflected in this finding aid.
History of the Collection
Search Terms
National Society of New England Women--History--Sources; Clipper. Newsletter of the National Society of New England Women; New England Kurn Hattin Homes, Inc.; Slade, Emma M.R. Hardy; New England--Genealogy--Sources; History--Societies, etc.--United States--Sources; Women in charitable work--United States; Women--Societies and clubs--United States--History--Sources; Conservatism--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Patriotic societies--United States--History--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
Associated material can be found in the National Society of New England Women. New York City Colony Records, Sophia Smith Collection. The NSNEW has published its quarterly newsletter (see the Sophia Smith Collection periodical collection) since 1963.
- SERIES I. NATIONAL--GENERAL
  - General
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Charters, 1895, 1900, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Constitution and By-laws, 1900-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Constitution and By-laws, 1950-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - History
      - General
        - 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - booklets, c.1905, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - brochure, 1971, 1975, 1977, 1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - certificates, 1968, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - minutes and reports, 1903-1921 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Round Robin, 1903-1911 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Slade, Emma Hardy
        - The Life Story of (mss), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - The Life Story of (enclosures), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Statue of the Pilgrim Maiden
        - The Story of the, 1934-1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Dedication, scrapbook, 9/4/24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - enclosures, 9/4/24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - photocopy, 9/4/24 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Memorabilia, 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Newsletter, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Poems and Songs, 1908, 1923, 1930, 1942, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Programs
      - Colony Day, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Founder's Day Luncheon (incomplete), 1937-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Ritual, creed, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Scrapbooks
      - clippings, 1895-1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - photographs, 1935, 1949-1960, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - photographs, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - history, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - national clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Past National Officers Association, 1972-1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - publicity clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        - 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 30)
        - 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 31)
        - 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        - 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 33)
        - 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- SERIES II. NATIONAL--ANNUAL CONGRESSES AND CONVENTIONS
  - Annual Congresses
    - minutes, 1913-1924 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - minutes, program, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - reports, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - minutes, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - minutes, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - minutes, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - minutes, notes, program, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - call, minutes, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - minutes, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - minutes, program, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - program, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - program, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - program, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - call, programs, song, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - program, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - call, minutes, program, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - program, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - call, programs, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - badge, programs, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - badge, call, minutes, news clippings, programs, song, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - programs, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - badge, programs, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - programs, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - programs, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - badge, programs, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - badges, minutes, programs, reports, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - programs, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - program, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - programs, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - badge, program, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - badge, program, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - call, program, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - program, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - program, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - photographs, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - call, programs, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - badge, call, programs, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - call, minutes, programs, reports, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - minutes, reports, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - badge, call, program, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - badge, call, program, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - minutes, programs, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - minutes, programs, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - programs, proposed resolutions, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - badge, call, photographs, programs, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - programs, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - photographs, programs, proposed resolutions, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - programs, proposed resolutions, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - programs, proposed resolutions, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - program, proposed resolutions, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - proposed resolutions, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - call, proposed resolutions, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - adopted resolutions, proposed resolutions, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - call, minutes, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - call, proposed resolutions, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - minutes, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - call, minutes, proposed resolutions, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - call, minutes, report, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - call, minutes, program, proposed by-laws changes, proposed resolutions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - call, memorial list, minutes, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - call, minutes, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - call, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - call, minutes, program, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - minutes, news release, pre-call, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - call, minutes, pre-call, program, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - call, pre-call, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - call, program, proposed resolutions, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Conventions
    - minutes, 1/23/13 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - minutes, 3/8/13 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - minutes, 4/14/13 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - minutes, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 71)
- SERIES III. NATIONAL OFFICERS
  - President General
    - address, 1910, 1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 1922, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 1930-1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - 1955-1956, 1959, 1964-1968, 1983, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - reports, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - scrapbook, Mrs. Parlan Semple Jr., 1934-1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - First Vice President General
    - correspondence, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Second Vice President General
    - correspondence, 1961, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Recording Secretary General
    - correspondence, 1935, 1963, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - memoirs, 1925-1929 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - reports, 1914, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Corresponding Secretary General
    - correspondence, 1960-1968, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - reports, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Organizing Secretary General
    - correspondence, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - preliminary organization procedure, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - subjects
      - Abigail Adams Colony, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Blue Grass Colony, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Boston Purchase Colony, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Carolina Capital Colony, c.1984 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Grace Sherman Livermore Colony, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Hannah Coolidge Charter Denied, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Love Samborne Graham Colony, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Minnesota Colony, c.1980 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Mountain Top Colony, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Old Monmouth, Colony of, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Suncoast Colony, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Sycamore Colony, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Three Flags Colony, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Treasurer General
    - audit, 1963-1974, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - correspondence, 1959, 1961, 1968, 1970, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Bessie Talbot Strongman Estate, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Flora Louise Henn Estate, 1963-1967 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Steinke Estate, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - forms, blank, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - record book, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - 1940-1945 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - 1945-1949 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - 1955-1959 (day ledger) (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - 1961-1964 (general ledger) (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Helping Hand Fund ledger, 1931-1936 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - other ledgers, 1938-1946 (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - 1958 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - proposed budgets, 1960-1962, 1966-1968, 1975-1977, 1983-1984, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - reports, 1958-1961, c.1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - 1965-1969, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 48)
      - 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Registrar General
    - correspondence, 1956, 1957, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      - 1972-1973, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 53)
      - subjects, advice to Colony Registrars, 1933, 1949, 1955 1965-1968, c.1971, c.1981, undated (Box 8, Folder 54)
      - subjects, microfilming, 1961-1972 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - financial records, dues paid, 1895-1945 (Box 9, Folder 56)
      - expenses, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 57)
      - remittance received, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - forms, blank, undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - membership lists, c.1899-1913 (Box 9, Folder 60)
      - #9290-15209, c. 1920's-1940's (Box 9, Folder 61)
      - 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 62)
      - new members and reinstatements, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - dropped, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 64)
      - transfers, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 65)
      - resignations, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 66)
      - deaths, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 67)
      - gains, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 68)
      - members under 40, reports, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 69)
      - deaths, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - cradle roll and junior members, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 71)
        - 1917-1974 (Box 9, Folder 72)
        - 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 73)
      - National Officers, 1968-1971, 1984-1990 (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - Colony Presidents, 1915-1916 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Colony Officers, c.1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - membership status change forms, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - permits, insignia, for officers, 1948-1957, 1967-1974, for members 1947-1973 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - marker, banner, c.1940's-1950's (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - reports, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 80)
      - 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 81)
      - 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 82)
      - 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 83)
      - 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 84)
      - 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 85)
      - 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 86)
      - 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - reports of colonies, annual, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 88)
      - 1966 (Box 11, Folder 89)
      - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 90)
      - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 91)
      - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 92)
      - junior members, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 93)
      - A-L, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 94)
      - M-Z, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 95)
      - 1971 (Box 12, Folder 96)
      - 1972 (Box 12, Folder 97)
      - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 98)
      - 1976 (Box 12, Folder 99)
      - 1977 (Box 12, Folder 100)
      - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 101)
      - 1979 (Box 13, Folder 102)
      - 1980 (Box 13, Folder 103)
      - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 104)
      - 1982 (Box 13, Folder 105)
      - 1983 (Box 13, Folder 106)
    - membership books, bound, No. l l9l4-l928 (Box 14, Folder 107)
      - No. 2 l925-l949 (Box 14, Folder 108)
      - No. 3 l947-l984 (Box 14, Folder 109)
  - Historian General, address to the Glen Falls Colony, 10/24/39 (Box 15, Folder 110)
    - correspondence, February 1970 (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - essay contest, 1969-1984 (Box 15, Folder 112)
  - Director General of Juniors, correspondence, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - lists and reports, 1967, 1969-1971,1985 (Box 15, Folder 114)
- SERIES IV. NATIONAL BOARDS
  - National Boards
    - minutes, 12/19/13-4/4/14 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - 5/2/14-12/19/14 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - 1914-1916 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - 1/9/15-12/27/15 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - 1915-1917 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - 2/5/16-12/27/16 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - 1917-1919 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - 1/6/17-4/7/17 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - 4/14/17-12/14/17 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - 2/2/18-12/14/18 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - 3/1/19-4/30/19 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - 10/7/19-4/20/21 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - 1920 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - 3/2/20-12/15/20 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - 3/15/21-12/13/21 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - 1/10/22-12/12/22 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - 1/9/23-4/10/23 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - 5/1/23-4/14/24 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - 5/5/24-4/14/25 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - 5/7/25-5/3/26 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - 5/7/25-5/3/26 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - 5/6/26-5/2/27 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - 5/6/26-5/5/27 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - 1/11/27 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - 5/5/27-4/30/28 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - 6/7/27-4/30/28 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - 5/3/28-5/6/29 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - 5/3/28-4/9/29 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      - 5/9/29-4/8/30 (Box 16, Folder 29)
      - 5/9/29-4/8/30 (Box 16, Folder 30)
      - 5/5/30-4/13/31 (Box 16, Folder 31)
      - 5/5/30-4/13/31 (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - 5/12/31-4/11/32 (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - 5/12/31-4/11/32 (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - 5/10/32-4/30/33 (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - 5/10/32-5/3/33 (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - 5/3/33-5/22/34 (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - 10/10/33-5/22/34 (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - 5/30/34-4/9/35 (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - 5/30/34-5/20/35 (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - 6/11/35-12/10/35 (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - 5/24/39-4/9/40 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - 5/20/40-4/9/41 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - 5/15/41-3/17/42 (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - 5/18/42-5/21/42 (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - 5/21/42-3/9/43 (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - 10/13/42-3/12/46 (Box 17, Folder 47)
      - 5/17/43-3/28/44 (Box 17, Folder 48)
      - 5/15/44-3/13/45 (Box 17, Folder 49)
      - 5/14/45-3/12/46 (Box 17, Folder 50)
      - 5/16/46-5/14/47 (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - 5/17/47-3/9/48 (Box 17, Folder 52)
      - 5/12/48-1/25/49 (Box 17, Folder 53)
      - 5/10-14/49-3/14/50 (Box 17, Folder 54)
      - 5/22/50-3/6/51 (Box 17, Folder 55)
      - 5/16/51-3/11/52 (Box 18, Folder 56)
      - 5/14/52-3/10/53 (Box 18, Folder 57)
      - 5/19/53-3/9/54 (Box 18, Folder 58)
      - 5/24/54 (Box 18, Folder 59)
      - 5/27/54-1/23/58 (Box 18, Folder 60)
      - 10/16/57-3/19/58 (Box 18, Folder 61)
      - 10/16/58-5/21/59 (Box 18, Folder 62)
      - 10/15/59-3/19/60 (Box 18, Folder 63)
      - 5/22/60-3/21/62 (Box 18, Folder 64)
      - 5/25/60-3/20/62 (Box 18, Folder 65)
      - 5/20/62-3/11/64 (Box 18, Folder 66)
      - 5/21/62-3/11/64 (Box 18, Folder 67)
      - 1963-1966 (Box 19, Folder 68)
      - 5/17/64-5/19/65 (Box 19, Folder 69)
      - 5/18/64-10/20/65 (Box 19, Folder 70)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 71)
      - 1/19/66-3/14/67 (Box 20, Folder 72)
      - 1/20/66-3/15/67 (Box 20, Folder 73)
      - 5/14/67-10/9/68 (Box 20, Folder 74)
      - 5/16/67-10/9/68 (Box 20, Folder 75)
      - 1/23/69-1/18/73 (Box 20, Folder 76)
      - 3/12/69-1/18/73 (Box 20, Folder 77)
      - 1/17/74-10/23/74 (Box 20, Folder 78)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 79)
      - 1/23/75-10/20/76 (Box 21, Folder 80)
      - 10/15/75-1/19/77 (Box 21, Folder 81)
      - 1/20/77-5/18/78 (Box 21, Folder 82)
      - 5/15/77-1/26/78 (Box 21, Folder 83)
      - 5/14/78-10/1/80 (Box 21, Folder 84)
      - 10/12/78-10/80 (Box 21, Folder 85)
      - 5/18/81-10/6/82 (Box 21, Folder 86)
      - 5/16/83-5/12/86 (Box 21, Folder 87)
- SERIES V. NATIONAL COMMITTEES
  - American Defense Committee, lecture, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Clarke School for the Deaf Committee, correspondence, 1969, 1971, 1976, 1981-1984, 1986, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - The Clipper, general, 1982, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Colony Committee, by-laws, colony, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - minutes, 1904-1906, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - reports, Round Robin, 1902-1922 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Emma Slade Hardy Student Loan Fund Committee
    - correspondence, 1949, 1955-1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Baldwin-Wallace College, 1962-1966 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Middlebury College, 1961-1966 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - St. Lawrence University, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - financial records, 1954-1966 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - guarantee notes, 1949, 1955-1956, 1960, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - honor book, 1937-1947 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - honor book, vol. II, 1947-1956 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - loan applicant ancestry records, 1950-1956, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - recipient data, 1937-1952 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - reports, 1936-1950 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - 1951-1963 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - 1963-1966 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Founders' Day Committee, correspondence, c. 1969 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Genealogical Records Committee, genealogies, c. 1981 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Kurn Hattin Homes Fund Committee, 1955-1984 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Legislation Committee, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Maud Brown Pendleton Loan Fund Committee, 1955-1985 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Medal of Honor Committee, 1943, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Membership Committee, 1903-1917, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943, 1949, 1955, 1956, 1970-1972, 1974-1975, 1977, 1982-1985, 1988, undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Nominating Committee, correspondence and report, c. 1917-1921, 1955, 1961, 1970, 1972-1975, 1982, 1984-1987 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Preservation of Historical Documents, Committee for, note, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Program Lending Bureau, list of papers, c. 1956 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - papers, CA, CT (Box 23, Folder 31)